Natsume
Gosh, I must crush it soon.
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
I know you're in there. I want to talk.
いるんだろう　話がある
くるくる回る
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
駅のホーム
響くファンファーレ
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
ごめんね
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
運命が笑う
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
臨界点突破してんだ
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
限界なら既に去って
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
絶対的支配だって
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
崩壊
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
叫ぶよ
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter
翻译：英英 校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：wcaster
僕は目を閉じるよ
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
Did you enjoy the game in the hospital?
この間のゲームは楽しんでもらえたかしら
It's not so bad to be chasing once a while, is it?
偶には追う身になるのも悪くないでしょう
The hunter chases the beast and the beast chases the hunter.
ハンターが獣を追い　獣がハンターを追う
It's a neverending game of tag.
永遠の追い掛けっこね
I see your taste hasn't improved.
相変わらず悪趣味だな
Do you know why I'm painting your portrait?
私が何故貴方の肖像を描くか　分かる
It can be said that the canvas lays its subject bare.
キャンバスに描かれた物こそ　あるがままと言っていう
A live person doesn't think twice about telling lies.
生きている人間は平気で嘘をつく
That goes for me and you as you are now.
私も　そして今の貴方も
And so, I paint.
だから私は描く
The Kanba Takakura in my art is my truth.
アートの中の高倉冠葉こそが私の本当
Sweet whispers of love mean nothing to me.
甘い愛の囁きなど
私には何の意味もない
Love is but a word.
愛と言うのはただの言葉　単なる画面
Just a concept.
That momentary passion people believe to be love
人が恋だと信じる一時の激情も
is nothing more than the effects of hormones on the brain.
所詮脳内を駆け巡るホルモンの影響に過ぎない
Tell me, how much do you love me?
ねえー
私の事　どのくらい愛してる
Knock it off!
やめろ　お前は単なるストーカーだ
You're just a stalker!
Stalker?
ストー　カー
This world is just a love hunting zone.
この世界は愛の狩猟区
You might say I'm a love hunter.
言うならば　私は愛の狩りウッド
True love that seeks naught return.
見返りを求めない真実の愛
It's about possessing true form of the object of one's affection.
それは相手の　本当の形を所有する事
Those who fail merely shoot themselves in the foot.
それが出来ぬ者は自らの銃で己が身を撃ちて　滅びるだけ
私は愛の勝利者　そして貴方は私の獲物
I am a victor in love.
And you are my prey.
Who you calling prey, ho?
誰がお前の獲物なんかに
You don't get it, do you?
分かってないのね
To enjoy the hunt, both parties must be on equal footing.
狩りを楽しむにはお互いの力が均衡していなければ
My match is you.
私と釣り合うのは貴方　貴方に釣り合うのは私
And your match is me.
This hunt is fate.
この狩りは運命
I have no time to play games with-
お前の遊びに付き合ってる暇は
Silence!
黙れ
Have you forgotten what you told me back then?
忘れたの　あの時私に言ってくれた事
It was just some nonsense I spouted as a kid. Let it go.
子供の時の戯言だ　忘れろ
これを
About this…
Kanba - Asami's hospital room - Balls that struck their foreheads - *What are those balls? The victims lost their memories.
Did you get it from that place, by any chance?
まさか　あそこから持ち出したのか
I made those girls forget about you.
彼女たちには貴方の事を忘れてもらったわ
狩人足る資格のない愚かな娘たち
Those foolish girls weren't qualified to hunt.
But I did this to keep your secret.
でもこれは貴方の秘密を守るためにした事
何の事だよ
What are you talking about?
No need to hide, I know everything about you.
いいのよ　私は貴方の全てを知っているのだから
I have no secrets!
俺に秘密なんてない
Don't give me that bullshit!
いい加減な事を言うな
It'll eventually become public even if I keep quiet about it.
私が黙っていても何れ世間に知られるわ
You'll fall off the cliff and tumble into the sea at this rate.
貴方このままだと　氷壁から海に落ちてしまうわ
What are you blabbering about now?
今度は何の話だ
I'm talking about the Emperor Penguin.
南極の皇帝ペンギンよ
A flock of penguins on the edge of an iceberg wavering about diving into the sea.
氷壁の水際で飛び込むのを躊躇っている大勢のペンギンたち
They only need one to dive in to find out if the sea is teaming with ferocious seals.
彼らのうちに一羽が飛び込めば
海の中に獰猛なアザラシがいるかどうかが分かる
But of course, no one wants to die.
無論誰も死にたくはないわ
So they wait, relentlessly.
だから彼らはひたすら待つの
Swaying on the ice, hoping for an unfortunate soul to fall into the sea.
氷の上で押し合いながらついてない誰かが海に落ちていくのを
You're saying I'll become one of those dumb penguins?
俺がその間抜けなペンギンになると
It's that kind of a place.
あそこはそういう所よ
分かっているでしょう
You know that.
Whatever, let's get down to the business.
それより　要件だ
Give me back Ringo Oginome's diary.
荻野目リンゴの日記を返してくれ
We need it.
俺たちにはあれが必要なんだ
I can't do that.
それは出来ないわ
Why not?
どうしてだ　あれはお前にとってただのゲーム
If it was just a game to you...
We need the diary too.
私たちにも日記は必要なの　分かったでしょう
Do you see it now?
I'm not handing over the diary.
日記は渡さない
Even if I had to fight you for it to save Mario.
マリオさんの命を救うためなら　仮令貴方と相争う事になったとしても
Who would've thought the curse from 16 years ago would take this form?
まさかこんな形で　十六年前の呪いが実現するとはね
What drama! What a fate!
なんというドラマ　なんという運命
Yes. He doesn't seem to realize that we have only obtained half of the diary.
ええ　私たちは半分しか日記を確保していない事　気づいてないよね
But it's pointless now.
でもこれでは意味がないのよ
The important part is...
肝心の部分が
ええ　もう半分の行方を早急に調べてくださらない
Yes.
Could you promptly find the other half for me?
Looks like you're all better.
体　もう大丈夫みたいね
Why did you hand over the diary?
どうして日記を渡しちゃったんだ
What do you mean why?
どうしてって
Today's
Slogan
ひまりの命を救うにはあれが必要だって知ってるだろう
You knew we needed it to save Himari's life.
And you gave it away so easily.
それにあんな簡単に
So easily?
簡単
Yeah.
そうだよ　ちょっと誘拐されて脅されたくらいで
What kind of a fool caves in to a little threat after a kidnapping?
渡しちゃう馬鹿があるかよ
Fool?
馬鹿
Fool.
Changed
Everything
That One
Word
何で打つんだよ
Why did you hit me?
You're right.
その通りよ　私が馬鹿だった
I was a fool.
Huh?
Little threat my ass!
何かちょっと脅されてよ
Do you know how worried I was?
人がどれだけ心配したか
Do you know how I felt when I let it go?
あたしがどんな思いであれを手放せたと思ってんの
They should've sliced you into 3cm cubes,
貴方なんかメスで完成近くに切り刻まれて
バーナー強火でこんがり狐に炙られちゃったらよかったのよ
and scorched you up with torches until you were golden-brown!
I can't believe I exchanged Momoka's diary for such a loser!
大切な桃果の日記をこんな人に引き換えにするなんて
My life is ruined!
あたしの人生設計めちゃくちゃよ
It must be a punishment for giving up on destiny.
きっとこれは運命を諦めようとした私への罰なんだわ
Right, the diary was your sister's...
そうか　あの日記は君のお姉さん
But it's all right.
でも大丈夫　プロジェクトMを再開するわ
I will resume the Project M.
I remember some of it.
日記の内容は少しなら覚えてる
I'll continue from where I left off.
続きを実行するわ
You're going to stalk Tabuki again?
また多蕗のストーカーを
I'm his real wife.
あたしは彼の本当の妻よ
Tonight, He and I will spend an exceptionally romantic night together.
そう　今夜多蕗さんと私は飛び切りロマンデェックな夜を過ごす
I think it was written in the diary.
確か日記に書かれていたわ
"I"? That's not you.
私って　それは君の事じゃないだろう
Momoka is me. That's fate.
桃果はあたし　それが運命なの
You're out of your mind!
可笑しいよ
You're you, nobody else.
君は君　他のだれでもないじゃないか
I'm not helping you.
手伝わないよ
Because I don't have the diary anymore?
あたしが日記を持ってないから
Pretending to be your sister is not going bring back what you have lost.
お姉さんの振りなんかしたって
失ったものは取り戻せないよ
Probably never will.
多分永久に
そう　なら　結構
Okay, fine.
I'll do it by myself.
一人でやるわ　これまでだって　ずっとそうしてきたんだから
Like I always have.
Goodbye.
さよなら
How to get your man, using any means necessary
Click Now
Entrance
Dulcamara's
Magic Potion Class
Plant
Snake
Frog
Other
Ladychanted Frog
Ladychanted Frog.
ヒメホマレガエル
Miraculous frog that surfaces once every 16 years.
十六年に一度だけ地上に現れる奇跡の蛙
Place this frog onto a 16-year-old girl's face and make her sweat.
これ蛙を十六歳女子の顔面に乗せ　汗をかかせる
Collect 18mL of the sweat and make the man of your dreams drink it.
その汗十八ミリリットルを採集し　意中の男性に飲ませると
Voila! He'll be head over heels for you.
あら　不思議
彼はたちまち貴方の虜　愛を告白せずにはいられないでしょう
He'll have no choice but to declare his love for you.
Voila! He'll be head over heels for you...
あら　不思議
彼はたちまち貴方の虜
No!
無理無理無理無理
Yuck, yuck, yuck!
No way in hell!
絶対無理無理無理無理
What's the urgent matter you had to discuss with me?
どうしたの　急に話がしたいだなんて
Sorry for calling you out.
すみません　お呼び掛けしちゃって
Um, where will Yuri be tonight?
あの　今夜百合さんは
She should be busy practicing for the show by now.
今頃稽古の真っ最中じゃないかな
The final show is approaching. She's working late every night.
もうすぐ楽日だし
毎晩遅くまで張り切ってるよ
I see.
そうなんですか
Have some coffee.
コーヒーをどうぞ
I made it with some special water.
特別な水で入れてみました
Thanks!
ありがとう
It'll warm you right up!
温まりますよ
It does have a mysterious aroma.
確かにちょっと不思議な香りがするね
A gamey scent.
野生的って言うか
Tabu...ki?
多蕗　さん
Ribbit.
ケロ
T-Tabuki?
多蕗さん
Oh, no!
そんな
What should I do...
どうしよう
I love you, Ringo!
好きだ　リンゴちゃん
Madly in love!
愛してる
What did you just say?
今　何って
I love you.
好きなんだ
Ah, I can no longer suppress this feeling.
この気持ちはもう抑え様がない
I'm in love with you.
君を愛してる
Tonight, I have come to take you away!
今夜僕は君を攫いに来た
Take me away! My prince!
攫ってください　王子様
Why didn't I realize this before?
何故今まで気が付かずにいたのだろう
The only place I could rest my wings was the fountain of love welling up in your eyes!
僕という渡り鳥が羽を休めるのは
君の瞳に湧く愛の泉しかなかったのに
Take a look, Ringo.
ほら　ご覧　リンゴちゃん
Ringo
Keiju
How beautiful!
素敵
There's a happy end waiting for us, right?
私達　幸せになりますよね
As the diary has shown us.
日記がそう示した通りに
Keiju
Ringo
Of course!
Hachiko
当たり前じゃないか
We were bound by fate before you were even born!
君が生まれる前から　僕らは運命で結ばれていたんだ
Everything that happened 'til now was just a love opera.
これまでの事はちょっとしたラブオペラ
Trials of love.
愛の試練だったんだ
Cupid's real arrow is, look...
本物のキューピッドの矢は
ほら
ここに
Right here!
Strike!
ストライク
Je t'aime mon amour.
Je t'aime mon amour
To the chateau of love!
愛の斜塔へ
We will sing forever.
二人で歌い続けるのさ
Tabuki... We have finally become one...
多蕗さん
私達　やっと一つに
If failure and despair are the will of fate,
失敗も失望も　それが運命の意図する事ならば
then I'm sure there's a meaning to everything.
きっと全てのことに意味がある
Not a single tear is wasted.
無駄に流す涙なんて　一滴もない
Why are you crying?
どうして泣くの
I don't know.
分からない
I have been yearning for this moment...
私はこの時を桃果と一つになれる日を
For the day I could become one with Momoka.
ずっと待ち望んでいたはずなのに
Then let your feelings take over.
だったら　その気持ちに素直になって
Sho! The pot's boiling over!
ああ　晶ちゃん　お鍋噴き零れてるよ
Geez! Why did you space out?
もうどうしたの　ボウットして
Sorry.
御免
Something happened between you and Ringo, didn't it?
晶ちゃん　リンゴちゃんと何かあったでしょう
Huh?
えー　別に何もないよ
N-Nothing happened!
You usually make stuffed cabbage when you want to make up with someone.
晶ちゃんがロールキャベツ作る時って
大抵誰かと仲直りしたい時なんだよね
Although, Kan was the only one you had to fight with.
と言ってもこれまで喧嘩相手と言ったら　冠ちゃんしかいなかったけど
Let's hope Ringo likes stuffed cabbage, too!
リンゴちゃんもロールキャベツ好きだといいね
Don't take it the wrong way!
ご　誤解するなよ　荻野目リンゴとは
She and I don't have that kind of...
なんていうか　そういう関係じゃ
分かってます
I know.
But she's your sister's precious friend, so be sure to make up!
だけど　妹の貴重な女友達なんだから
ちゃんと仲直りすること
Little sister's orders!
妹命令です
No!
だめ
No... I can't do it.
だめ　やっぱり出来ないよ
Why not?
どうして
I mean, we love each other so much!
だって　僕達はこんなにも愛し合っているじゃないか
Love?
愛　あたしは多蕗さんを愛してる
Do I love you?
Aren't we destined lovers?
運命の恋人のはずだろう
I'm not...
あたし　違う
I'm sorry, Tabuki.
御免なさい　多蕗さん
I'm going home.
あたし　帰ります
ケロ
Ribbit.
What?
ケロ
Ribbit?
Tabu...ki?
多蕗　さん
ケロ　ケロ　ケロ　ケロ　ケロ　ケロ　ケロ　ケロ　ケロー
Ladychanted Frog
N-No!
嫌ー
リンゴちゃん　開けてくれ
Ringo!
Open it for me!
ケロ　ケロ
リンゴちゃん　愛してるんだ
I love you Ringo... Ribbit!
Don't be scared.
怖がらないで　ケロ
Ribbit!
Oh, welcome.
あら　いらっしゃい
Y-Yuri?
ゆ　百合さん
Ringo!
リンゴちゃん
Open ribbit, Ringo!
リンゴちゃん　開けてケロ
Yuri!
百合さん　（ねえ　リンゴちゃん）
Hey, Ringo!
Please break up with Tabuki!
多蕗さんと別れてください
Ringo... make me your beloved birdy!
リンゴちゃん　僕を君の小鳥にしておくれ　（えー）
I love you, Ringo!
愛してるんだ　リンゴちゃん
Oh, my!
You heard that?
聞いたでしょう　（開けろ）
Tabuki can no longer love any other woman.
多蕗さんはもうあたし以外の女の人を愛せない体になってしまったんです
だから　多蕗を私にください
So give him to me!
Hey, open up, Ringo!
Sure.
いいわよ
Go on a tandem flight of love with me!
But will that really make you happy?
でもそれで貴方は幸せになれるのかしら
Ringo!
Of course I will!
なるに決まってます
I'll marry Tabuki, live in a little house,
多蕗さんと結婚して　小さいな家を建てて
and become a happy family with a puppy and a baby!
子犬と子供と　家族みんなで幸せになるんです
I'd thought you were in love with Shoma Takakura.
私はてっきりリンゴちゃんは高倉晶馬君の事が好きなのだと思ってたわ
What?
え
I knew it! You are in love with him.
ほら　やっぱり　貴方はあの子が好きなのね
Love? Me?
好き　私が
そうよ　大馬鹿さん
Yes, silly girl!
You didn't even realize your true feelings.
本当の気持ちにも気づかないなんて
I'm in love with... Shoma?
あたしが晶馬君を　　好き
I should make some fabulous tea.
さぁー　ファビュラスのお茶でも入れようかしら
Caution: However, its effect lasts one night only
so use it only as a last resort.
Ringo!
リンゴちゃん　開けてケロ
Open ribbit!
My love is unstoppable!
愛が止まられんだ
あ　リンゴちゃん　御帰り
Welcome back, Ringo!
Himari...
ひまりちゃん　どうしてここに
Why are you here?
Um...
あのう　今晩は
Good evening.
You're home late.
随分遅かったね
So what?
だったら　何
I was wondering if you were hungry.
お腹空いてないかと思って
I made this with Himari.
これひまりと作ったんだ
Ta-da! The Takakura secret recipe: Stuffed Curry Cabbage!
ジャン　高倉家特製カレー味ロールキャベツ
You like curry, right?
荻野目さん　カレー好きだったよね
We made too much.
ちょっと作り過ぎちゃったからさ
That's why I hate you...
だから嫌なのよ
It's all your fault!
全部　貴方が悪いんじゃない
What?
何で打つんだよ
Why did you hit me?!
I love Tabuki!
あたしは多蕗さんが好きなの
ええ
I'm in love with Tabuki!
あたしは多蕗さんを愛してるの
So I'll marry him and become Momoka!
だから彼と結ばれて桃果になる
That's fate! The reason I was born!
それが運命　あたしの生まれた理由
家族の輪を繋ぐ最後の手段
The last option I had to connect the family loop!
You wrecked it!
貴方が打ち壊したんじゃない　あたしの運命にずかずか土足で入り込んで来て
You waltzed into my fate and ruined all my hard work!
いままでの努力が全部水だわ
Why?
どうして
ええ
Why did you come into my life?
どうして　貴方はあたしの前に現れたの
Why did you have to say I'm me?
どうして　あたしはあたしだなんて言ったの
どうして　どうして
Why... why?!
What are you to me?
貴方はあたしの何なのよ
What... am I to you?
僕は君の　なんなんだろう
Survival Strategy!
生存戦略
イマージン
Imagine!
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
きっと何者にも成れないお前達に告げる
Cry, monkey bitch.
泣け　雌猿
I will make an exception and allow it.
この際　特別に許可してやる
Screech out your tears and let it all out.
悲喜喚いて
あらいざらい全部ぶちまけてしまえ
You know about our Curry Day tradition, right?
うちのカレーの日は知ってるでしょう
Uh... Yeah.
ああ　うん
On the day of month when my sister, Momoka Oginome passed away,
姉の荻野目桃果の月命日には
we as family eat her favorite food, curry.
彼女の好物だったカレーを家族で食べる
That's the family rule.
それが我が家のルール
I never knew.
そうだったんだ
On that day 16 years ago, my sister passed away.
十六年前のその日　姉が亡くなった
And I, Ringo, was born on the same day.
そして同じ日にあたし　リンゴが生まれた
16 years ago... You mean...
十六年前って　まさか
ええ　そのまさかよ
Yes, exactly.
My sister, Momoka Oginome is a victim of that incident.
あたしの姉　荻野目桃果はあの事件の犠牲者なの
Do you get it now?
だから　分かるでしょう
I was born as my sister died.
姉の死と同時に生まれたあたしは桃果の生まれ変わりなの
I'm Momoka's reincarnation.
I wanted to be with Tabuki.
多蕗さんと一緒になりたかった
貴方があたしの前に現れなければ全て上手く行ったのよ
Everything would've gone according to plan if only you never showed up!
What's wrong?
何よ　何時みたいに何が言いなさいよ
Talk back like you always do.
No...
いや　君の言う通りだ
You're right.
I was the one who messed up your fate in the first place!
そもそも　十六年前のその日　君の運命を狂わせたのは僕なんだから
Don't be absurd! 16 years ago, you weren't even...
馬鹿言わないで
十六年前って言ったら　貴方だってまだ
Born? My brother, Kanba, and I were born on that day.
生まれたんだ
その日に僕と兄貴冠葉が生まれた
And it's our fault your sister passed away.
そして　僕達のせいで　君のお姉さんは亡くなった
What... are you saying?
何を　言ってるの
I'm saying your sister died...
だから　君のお姉さんが死んだのは僕達のせいなんだ
and we're to blame!
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
生存戦略　しましょうか
You Have Finally Realized It
全てが欲しい
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
繋がれたいたら
僕らはどうして
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
もがくのだろう
それは君じゃない
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
君のせいじゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
だからそうじゃない
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
夢のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
上手く伝えきれないけど
Dear my future
Dear your future
Dear you future
That's right. We're to blame for everything.
そうさ　全て僕達のせいなんだ
We're the ones who messed up your fate.
君の運命を狂わせたのは僕達だ
It's our sin. You and I are...
これは僕達の罪で君と僕は
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy. Little sister's orders.
生存戦略　妹命令